In Unity a script is considered as a custom
Unity においてスクリプトはカスタムの
component, and often you will need to access
コンポーネントと捉えられていて、
other scripts attached to the same gameobject
しばしば同じゲームオブジェクトにアタッチされているスクリプトをアクセスしたり
or even on other gameobjects.
あるいは別のゲームオブジェクトの場合でもアクセスが必要な場合があります。
You can access other scripts and components
他のスクリプトやコンポーネントにアクセスするには
using GetComponent.
GetComponent を使用します。
In this example both AnotherScript and
このサンプルでは AnotherScript および
YetAnotherScript both have public
YetAnotherScript の両方に public 変数が
variables within them.
が含まれています。
We'd like to be able to effect those variables
それらの変数についても
in our UsingOtherComponents script.
UsingOtherComponents スクリプトの中から変更したいとします。
We have three variables here.
ここに 3 つの変数があります。
One to store anotherGameObject,
ひとつは anotherGameObject を格納するためで、
and two to store references to the other
残りの 2 つは他のスクリプトへの参照を格納するためです。
scripts. Note that the references
他のスクリプトへの参照も
to the other scripts are simply variables
スクリプトの名前と同じ型の変数であることを
whose type is the name of the script.
覚えておくべきです。
This is because what we're actually referencing
これは実際にアクセスしているものがスクリプトで定義されている
is an instance of the class defined in the script.
クラスのインスタンスであるためです。
For more information see the lesson on
詳しくはこのレッスンの下にあるリンクから
classes linked below this lesson.
クラスに関するレッスンを参照して下さい。
In the Awake function we initialise
Awake 関数の中で変数を初期化
our variables. The GetComponent function
します。 GetComponent 関数は
uses a slightly different style of call
普段と少し違ったスタイルのコールを行って
to what we're use to. We use a pair of angle
います。通常の {} の前に <> を
brackets before the normal brackets.
使用しています。
These angle brackets are for taking a
これらの <> は型をパラメータとする場合に
type as a parameter, in our case the type
使用され、この場合に型は
will be AnotherScript. We can also call
AnotherScript です。さらに GetComponent をコールして
GetComponent to address components on
参照のある別のゲームオブジェクト、
other gameobjects that we have references
例えば otherGameObject 、にある
to, like otherGameObject.
コンポーネントをみつけます。
GetComponent will return a reference
GetComponent はコールされたゲームオブジェクト上にある
to any component of the type specified
指定された型のコンポーネントへの参照を
on the gameobject it is called upon.
戻り値とします。
So in this example I'm addressing my
例えばこのサンプルでは、
anotherScript, which is on the same object
メインスクリプトである UsingOtherComponents と同じオブジェクトにある
as UsingOtherComponents, my main script.
anotherScript をみつけます。
So I can say GetComponent and address
GetComponent と書いて、PlayerScore を
the player score directly. But if I want
直接みつけることが出来ます。
to address the number of player deaths
しかし、Player Deaths の数を見つけたい場合は
I'll use otherGameObject.GetComponent
otherGameObject.GetComponent を使用して
to address the other script on the cube.
キューブ上の他のスクリプトをみつけます。
That way I can affect the number of player
これにより、 Player Deaths の数を
deaths directly.
直接変更することが出来ます。
Whilst GetComponent is most commonly
GetComponent 主に他のスクリプトを
used for accessing other scripts it
アクセスするのに使用しますが、
can also be used to access other components
API により公開されてない他のコンポーネントへの
that are not exposed by the API.
アクセスにも使用できます。
For example the collider that you normally
例えば Collider と入力することで
access by typing Collider is a non specific collider.
通常アクセスするコライダは不特定のコライダです。
A sphere collider has different properties
例えば Sphere Collider は、
to a box collider for example.
Box Collider と異なるプロパティです。
And if you want to access these properties
そしてこれらのプロパティを
in scripts you can do so by using GetComponent.
スクリプトでアクセスするには、 GetComponent を使用します。
For example, I can address the box collider
例えば、 OtherGameObject 上の
on the OtherGameObject by saying
Box Collider を見つけるには
boxCol is equal to otherGameObject dot GetComponent BoxCollider
boxCol が otherGameObject.GetComponent() と等しいかをみます。
I can then use my boxCol variable
これで boxCol 変数を使用して
to address any of the parameters
OtherGameObject にあるコンポーネントの全てのパラメータを
on that component on the OtherGameObject.
みつけることが出来ます。
So for example I can address the size
例えば Size をみつけて
and set it to 3 when the scene starts.
シーン開始時に 3 をセットできます。
Something to note about GetComponent
GetComponent について覚えておくべきことは、
is that it's expensive in terms of
処理負荷が高価であり、
processing power and should be called
できるかぎりコール回数を
as infrequently as possible.
抑えるべきです。
It's often good practice to call it in the
多くの場合において
Awake or Start functions, or only
Awake または Start 関数でコールするか、
once when it's first needed.
初めて必要になるときに一回だけコールすると良いです。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)